ANISLEY SAEZ V.

anisley.sv@gmail.com

Houston, TX

www.linkedin.com/in/anisleysv

WEB DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

Bilingual professional passionate about new technologies, fast learner with a can-do attitude and strong problem solving focus. 7+ years helping companies to get the most of technology by improving productive processes with software solutions and teaching professionals to develop the right technical skills. Well known for going the extra mile in my professional assignments. Bringing a unique perspective in the relation: clients needs -- technology -- solutions.

EDUCATION

MS in E-Learning, majoring in Educational Technology - 2014 BS in Information Technology, majoring in Computer Science - 2008

both titles earned at the University of Computer Science, Havana, Cuba (Named in Spanish: Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas - www.uci.cu)

SKILLS

Fast learner, problem solving, communication, creative, analytical thinking, object oriented programming, web design, organize, teamwork, leadership, public speaking.

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Java, C++, SQL.

Tools: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Atom, Git, GitHub, Netbeans, Postgresql, Visual Paradigm. **Others:** Slack, UML, UI, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular, AS-400, Moodle, Educational Technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOUTHWEST KEY PROGRAMS - Houston, Texas USA

2017 - 2018

Seasonal teacher

- Teaching several subjects to a multicultural youth.
- Planning Project Based Learning creative activities with the educational department.
- Using software tools such ETO, Sharepoint, Relias Learning to improve work performance.

COSTEX TRACTOR PARTS - Miami, Florida USA

2016 - 2017

Office clerk | Shipping coordinator

- Collaborating with the Technology Department to review and develop reports AS-400. *Reduced in 5% daily work efforts of shipping group due to the improvement of POE Reports Process.*
- Managing a database (enter, retrieve and remove data) with the AS-400 system.
- Developing multiple tasks in daily routine at an office fast paced environment.

UNIVERSITY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE - Havana, Cuba

2008 - 2016

Software Engineer | Assistant professor (2014-2016)

- Working in CALINFOR project and developing programs, web UI, media resources, objects and learning assignments for Moodle: Dreamweaver, HTML, CSS.
- Leading for almost 2 years a 5 member team of professors with different backgrounds and specializations.

- Acting as technical consultor during the design and implementation of educational products.
 Dozens of objects and learning assignments, web and media resources developed for the Institutional Learning Management System.
- Teaching graduate programs and conducting researches in the area of Educational Technology.

Software Engineer | Instructor (2008-2014)

- Performing research and problem solving tasks in projects: ALFAOMEGA, MPPEU and GALM.
 (Please consult "selected accomplishments" section for more details)
- Teaching Computer Science in the disciplines of Software Engineering and Programming Techniques, involving: Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Netbeans, Java, Relational Databases Design, Triggers, Postgresql, SQL.

SELECTED ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Built my **professional portfolio in 2018** and gained online visibility by learning how to use Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Git, GitHub, Atom, HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript to design a brand and develop interactive websites from scratch. Pursuing an specialization in Web Development (Break Into Tech Blueprint) **at SKILLCRUSH**.
- Helped UCI project managers to meet established deadlines and publish successfully results (please refer to linkedin profile accomplishments publications). Projects worked:

CALINFOR (Pedagogical research and Institutional Educational Platform support) **2014 - 2016** Roles: analyst, technical consultant, specialist in Educational Technology.

- Deployed new technologies, with a pedagogical foundation, in the Institutional Learning Management System (Moodle) to improve the System of Learning Resources used to teach Relational Database Design to future software engineers.
- Written the results mentioned above as thesis and presented in the option to the Master's degree in eLearning. Technologies involved: Postgresql, RDB, SQL.

MPPEU (Educational Platform)

2011 - 2013

Roles: specialist in in Educational Technology, UI designer

- Developed programs to compliment the function of the Educational Platform related to the use of e-books and e-readers; involving: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery.
- Supported the decision making process by providing a Technical report and a database with critical information for the development of the project. [Relational Database Design, Postgresql]

ALFAOMEGA (Educational Platform)

2010 - 2011

Roles: specialist in Standards for Content Management, Java developer.

- Helped to reach 100% customer satisfaction for the project first year milestones.
- Highly recognized personal performance in:
 - o selection of technologies and standards of content management for educational platform.
 - o team's technical instruction involving: SCORM, OOP, Java, Relational Database, SQL.

GALM (IDE for creating multimedia products, GPL licensed) Roles: analyst, developer, QA management

2007 - 2009

- Successfully developed the IDE Management Subsystem for Visual Interface Design (Picasso) by using Netbeans, C++, QT libraries, and the eXtreme Programming Methodology (pair programming).
- Written partial results as thesis and presented in the option to the Bachelor's degree.